# Michael Coffman – Backend Developer

HappyDevCom@outlook.com

# **Summary**

Deep understanding of many technical subjects.

Good experience in frontend development with great eye on creating pixel perfect and responsive layout.

Industry experience in web development from architectural design to implementation/deployment in both backend & frontend sides.

Having previous experience in Typescript/Node.js and Python.

I am an avid backend developer. I love to be creative and inventive. I have over 5 years of experience and the field. More documentation of experience, references and skills are available upon request.

#### **Work Experience**

## Back End Developer, Jan 2019 – current, HQ Software

- Helped rebuilding of v2 of landing page and dashboard and camp using React.js/Node.js
- Built REST API backend server with Node.js
- Worked with various databases like MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB
- Helped rerbuilding of v2 landing page and dashboard and camp using React.js/Node.js
- Upgraded the camp using TypeScript

#### • Back End Developer Jan 2016 - Dec 2018, Sophilabs

- Built AWS Serverless architecture for the backend API development and building
  Lambda functions using Python/Node
- Integrated RESTful APIs using Axios

### • Full-stack Developer, Aug 2014 - Dec 2015, Kaiser Permanente

Developed front end using JavaScript, React.js and back end with Node.js and
 Python

- Upgrade the webapp using MERN stack
- Developed Single Page Application with Redux and Stateless Component
- Developed internet e-commerce software

## Education

Kyoto University - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science April 2011 - June 2014

#### Skills

- Python (Django)
- SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB)
- Cloud (GCP, AWS)
- JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Nodejs, Express.js)
- Typescript
- HTML/ CSS, CI/CD